<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leon Stafford</title>
    <link>https://leonstafford.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Leon Stafford</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://leonstafford.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>WordCamp Brisbane 2018 - WordPress as a Static Site Generator</title>
      <link>https://leonstafford.github.io/blog/wordcamp_brisbane_2018_wordpress_as_a_static_site_generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leonstafford.github.io/blog/wordcamp_brisbane_2018_wordpress_as_a_static_site_generator/</guid>
      <description>In a tired, but inspired state, after attending this weekend&amp;rsquo;s WordCamp Brisbane 2018.
Got to start with a big shout-out to all of the organizers, volunteers, speakers and attendees - THANK YOU!
I&amp;rsquo;m far from a WordPress fanboi - I regularly talk people out of using self-hosted WordPress. As a tech industry professional, I feel responsible to not push everyone to use a certain technology unless it makes sense. For someone who isn&amp;rsquo;t interested in learning development and being responsible for security and performance of their server (or willing to pay someone else to be), I&amp;rsquo;d much sooner advise them to check-out a hosted platform, be it WordPress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tweaking the Bitnami WordPress Stack on AWS LightSail</title>
      <link>https://leonstafford.github.io/notes/lightsail_bitnami_wordpress_tweaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leonstafford.github.io/notes/lightsail_bitnami_wordpress_tweaks/</guid>
      <description>Tired of clunkily updating a GitHub gist, herein lie my notes used when provisioning an AWS LightSail instance with Bitnami WordPress for quick migration/debugging of an existing user&amp;rsquo;s WordPress site.
 copy public key via the virtual terminal in AWS Console set a DNS entry to point dev domain to the instance&amp;rsquo;s IP access site at dev domain rm bitnami banner  sudo /opt/bitnami/apps/wordpress/bnconfig --disable_banner 1 sudo /opt/bitnami/ctlscript.sh restart apache  SSH in using dev domain enable SSL  sudo mkdir /opt/bitnami/letsencrypt cd /opt/bitnami/letsencrypt sudo wget https://dl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business to feed the family</title>
      <link>https://leonstafford.github.io/essays/business_to_feed_the_family/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leonstafford.github.io/essays/business_to_feed_the_family/</guid>
      <description>Does the greed for extra profit margins cause more damage to the ecosystem?
 &amp;ldquo;I made a G today&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;but you made it in a sleazy way&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Selling crack to the kids&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;I gotta get paid!&amp;rdquo;
Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s this &amp;ldquo;I gotta get paid&amp;rdquo; part which I hear the most. People tell me how they&amp;rsquo;d love to work as a volunteer or work on social ventures. Then comes the big &amp;ldquo;but&amp;rdquo;, twerking to the tune of &amp;ldquo;I gotta feed my family&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persuasion for humanity</title>
      <link>https://leonstafford.github.io/essays/persuasion_for_humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leonstafford.github.io/essays/persuasion_for_humanity/</guid>
      <description>Not all advertising has to be evil
 Wanting to share your beliefs without imposing on the freedom of others
The healthy option Compromising on one&amp;rsquo;s values can slowly eat away at their sense of self, their confidence and their ability not to compromise in future situations. Perhaps this is contributing to global cases of mental health problems, in that we deep down can understand the effects of habitat destruction, but continue to compromise and consume the products which destroy it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short distance relationships</title>
      <link>https://leonstafford.github.io/essays/short_distance_relationships/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leonstafford.github.io/essays/short_distance_relationships/</guid>
      <description>Can&amp;rsquo;t live with/out them ? live close to them
 Does living apart from your partner defy the universally accepted love protocols?
Staying withing firing range Love&amp;rsquo;s great marksman, Cupid, drew back his arrow, he didn&amp;rsquo;t get into close quarters range for some Krav Maga nut shots.
TIL - The furthest recorded accurate shot in competitive archery was set at 283.47 metres in 2015. Definitely, people have maintained long distance relationships over greater distances than this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focusing at different levels</title>
      <link>https://leonstafford.github.io/essays/focusing_at_different_levels/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leonstafford.github.io/essays/focusing_at_different_levels/</guid>
      <description>Being social, spiritual or primal
 Can we balance all of these states of attention?
Accepting different levels of awareness I have written of my previous tendency to sway between extremes and this has made me more aware now of similar extremities in my focus of thoughts.
At different times, I think my main drivers have been those of:
 existentialism: packing life into a backpack at 20 to seek meaning in the world social: volunteering to perform a role in the greater community primal: doing the things we do to attract mates and continue our genes  When one of these seems futile or perhaps becomes boring, there has been a shift to another level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I believe</title>
      <link>https://leonstafford.github.io/essays/what_i_believe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leonstafford.github.io/essays/what_i_believe/</guid>
      <description>Proofless acceptance and self-justification
 Written more for my children and partner to help understand my actions.
Are questions more interesting than statements? &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s the point?&amp;rdquo; can often be exasperated in moments of depression. Rather than it&amp;rsquo;s usual negative lamentation, leading to frustration at the lack of evidential answers, we can choose to embrace it for the beauty of its limitless depth.
King&amp;rsquo;s Quest Yep, I love referencing old computer games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The true cost of everything</title>
      <link>https://leonstafford.github.io/essays/true_cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leonstafford.github.io/essays/true_cost/</guid>
      <description>Should vegans become rocks to minimize their impact on the earth and our ears?
 They may not answer in the affirmative to that, but where does their limit lie?
Sidetrack - Extremes and balances I tend to look at and often live in extremes, something I&amp;rsquo;ve become more aware of with a partner who notices these kinds of things.
 a hoarder or my life&amp;rsquo;s in my backpack obsessively vegan or binging on terrible food procrastinating or melded to the computer  The above highlight behaviours, but this also hits me when philosophizing about society and humanity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Leon</title>
      <link>https://leonstafford.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leonstafford.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Passionate about:
 low-resource computing automation open source  Open source developer specialising in static website performance optimisation Creator of WP Static Site Generator a plugin that solves some security, performance and cost issues with WordPress websites.
My development tooling I write code in Vim. As per the sound advice from The Pragmatic Programmer, learn one text editor well, manipulating text is an every day thing. Aim to be good, be fast and enjoy it!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>