<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on Leon Stafford</title>
    <link>https://leonstafford.github.io/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on Leon Stafford</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://leonstafford.github.io/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Low footprint tech hub</title>
      <link>https://leonstafford.github.io/notes/low_footprint_tech_hub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leonstafford.github.io/notes/low_footprint_tech_hub/</guid>
      <description>Aiming to create very low-cost, low-footprint self-contained workstations that can be deployed to areas lacking resources.
A place you go to invest in knowledge and develop skills
&amp;ldquo;The Knowledge Bank Network&amp;rdquo;
Functions:
 knowledge bank  offline WikiPedia, StackOverflow  entertainment  public domain movies, music, books, games  communications  share one connection   Ideas to explore:
raspberryPi control unit, acting as router, NAS - OpenBSD - dhcp - pf to share connection - local web server - shows network status - portal to documentation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep Your Core Strong - Know Your BSD/Linux Tools</title>
      <link>https://leonstafford.github.io/notes/keep_your_core_strong_know_your_bsd_linux_tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leonstafford.github.io/notes/keep_your_core_strong_know_your_bsd_linux_tools/</guid>
      <description>Just as the sage advice from The Pragmatic Programmer on mastering one text editor makes so much sense for those of us whose majority of work is rearranging bits on the digital titanic, the same holds true for knowing your operating system and investing in solid tooling for your other main productive tasks.
Opinionated preface - Open source or GTFO The world&amp;rsquo;s resources are quickly depleting. A growing population having to work sh!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tweaking the Bitnami WordPress Stack on AWS LightSail</title>
      <link>https://leonstafford.github.io/notes/lightsail_bitnami_wordpress_tweaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leonstafford.github.io/notes/lightsail_bitnami_wordpress_tweaks/</guid>
      <description>Update:
I no longer use Bitnami on AWS LightSail due to the steps required to get sane application behaviour and performance are not worth it. Leaving this up for any searches leading here and will recommend for a similar level of serviced hosting, try DigitalOcean or Vultr.
Tired of clunkily updating a GitHub gist, herein lie my notes used when provisioning an AWS LightSail instance with Bitnami WordPress for quick migration/debugging of an existing user&amp;rsquo;s WordPress site.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>